Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/danieldak (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Solution Architecture Software Engineering Microsoft Azure

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
ITIL v3 Foundation

Honors-Awards

Intermountain Healthcare Innovation Winner

Daniel D.

Enterprise Architecture Professional | Making Interoperability Work Salt Lake City Metropolitan Area

Summary

Experienced Enterprise and Solutions Architect, Software Engineer, leader, adviser, influencer, system-level thinker, coach, with passion for learning innovative technologies. Experience in leading teams in complex and business-critical enterprise solutions. Record of accomplishment of innovative designs and successful outcomes. Making Interoperability Work and helping the organization focus on how to "Do the right things" and "Do things right"!

Experience

SelectHealth
14 years 8 months

Principal Enterprise Solutions Architect
June 2014 - Present (6 years 6 months)

Greater Salt Lake City Area

- Lead Architect responsible for overall Interoperability architecture and direction for the company.
- Lead Solutions Architect for the Digital Front Door/Digital Transformation initiatives for SelectHealth, working with Intermountain Healthcare and BCG.
- Spearheader the planning and approval of multi-million TriZetto Facets re-platform project. Involving 200+ Applications, 100+ Services, and APIs, 600+ Batch Jobs, 200+ ETLs, reports, and over 3000 database objects. The project teams are comprised of onsite and offshore resources of more than 50 caregivers and contractors.
- Spearheaded Enterprise API Strategy and API Management across the organization, which enables engineering teams and integration partners to deliver quickly, safely, and sustainably. Platform-based on REST APIs, Microservices, PaaS
- Influenced container-based development practices using Docker
- Experience in designing and building highly-available services
- A key member of a team that was selected by Intermountain Healthcare
 Foundry a winner of a yearly innovation competition, where the team secured

funding for the idea centered around using machine learning and bots to provide a lower cost and more effective approach to claims processing.

- Key contributor in representing SelectHealth within the Intermountain Healthcare enterprise in moving applications to a new identity management platform
- Provide consulting for various IT teams
- Educate IT teams on new technologies and patterns and how they fit within the organization
- Developed libraries, frameworks, and API design guidelines and best practices
- A key contributor in defining architecture roadmaps for the business stakeholders
- Implemented TOGAF standards
- Created and maintained architecture blueprints for various solutions within the organization, in addition to defining and enforcing software standards and processes
- Robotic Process Automation

Senior Software Engineer Technical Lead April 2006 - June 2014 (8 years 3 months)

Greater Salt Lake City Area

- Spearheaded the creation of the SelectHealth .NET SDK's that are used across the organization
- Provided mentoring and guidance
- Responsible for detailed design, architecture, development, testing and maintained of complex enterprise applications providing access to confidential health and financial information
- Acted as Technical Lead on major initiatives
- Technical Lead on complex business-critical applications
- Leading teams of developers as many as 9 at one given time, which included on and offsite team members and contractors
- Key contributor to Public Healthcare exchange integration centered around solutions based on Microsoft BizTalk
- Provided proof of concept for technologies and tools
- Created technical solution specification for various applications
- Acted as a liaison between Software Engineering and Architecture teams
- Lead the effort in creating the SelectHealth Batch Framework that is used across the organization to create customized workflows and batch jobs
- Key contributor to Software Development standards and best practices

- Designed and developed lightweight Database Access Framework with support for various Databases
- Started the SelectHealth .NET User Group
- Developed encryption library with support for GPG, PGP, Certificates, and custom in-house encryption protocols
- Key contributor to our claims and payment processing solutions
- Spearheaded the team that upgraded legacy enterprise Visual Basic 6
 applications (50+ applications) to the current technologies
- Designed and developed high-quality, multi-threaded solutions
- Developed IBM FileNet lightweight Framework, that allows for full and easy communication with FileNet
- Developed custom SFTP library that is being used by applications across the organization
- Developed extensible logging library that allows integration with 3rd party logging frameworks
- Developed for and supported complex Batch environments
- -Written design, functional, technical, and operational documentation

Intermountain Healthcare Software Engineer January 2004 - April 2006 (2 years 4 months) Greater Salt Lake City Area

- UNIX development
- Experience in implementing complex reports using Crystal Reports
- Database schema design. Developing and optimization of complex SQL stored procedures, views, triggers and other database objects in Oracle, SAP Sybase ASE, and SQL Server
- Performed code reviews using manual and automated ways to ensure standards and guidelines are followed
- Delphi development and application support
- Web Application development using JSP, ASP, and ASP.NET
- Experience with mid to large Data conversion and migration both in Oracle and Sybase
- Developing secure applications (role-based security, authorization, authentication, and data encryption)
- Lead the initiatives in adopting .NET technologies
- Development and maintenance of Claim Auditing application

Education

Weber State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science · (2000 - 2003)

Activity

10/21/2020, Sundone Boutvyseth added candidate to Software Architect

11/06/2020, updated candidate from Software Architect

11/06/2020, Message sent by Bobby Aragon

11/06/2020, updated candidate from Software Architect

11/10/2020, Bobby Aragon added a note

@Sundone Boutvyseth This guy is interested and waiting for a message from you to chat. Times he's available to chat.

Tuesday: 8:30am, 10am, 2pm Wednesday: 12:30pm, 2pm

Thursday:10am

11/12/2020, Message sent by Sundone Boutvyseth

11/13/2020, Viewed by Sundone Boutvyseth